A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Phillips Academy (07850105), 1978 January 01-1978 December 31 (Reel R2280)
    Dissemination of the proceeding and findings of the andover symposium on learning in adolescence
    Lynch, Barbara D.; Saario, Terry
  - Phillips Academy (08100604), 1981 June 15-1983 December 14 (Reel R4364)
    Launch andover-dartmouth institute for teachers of secondary schl math. And con't math. And science for minority students (ms2)prog.
    $316,400.00; $312,370.63
    Nelson, Barbara S.
  - Phillips Academy (08450214), 1984 March 01-1986 December 31 (Reel R5063)
    Technical assistance to boarding schools with minority programs to establish summer programs for urban high school math teachers
    $44,350.00; $30,651.00
  - Phillips Academy (09101299), 1991 June 01-1995 February 28 (Reel R7485)
    Support for the institute for recruitment of teachers
    Hatton, Barbara R.; Beckham, Edgar F.
  - Phillips Brooks House Association, Incorporated (06900538), 1969 (Reel R1528)
    General support for the 1969-70 program of volunteer teachers for africa
  - Phillips Brooks House Association, Incorporated (09150153), 1990 December 01-1992 December 01 (Reel R6581)
    Support to worldteach for a program placing volunteer teachers in namibian secondary schools and teacher training colleges
    Fehnel, Richard A. (Richard Allen)
    Namibia
  - Phillips County Community College (09700757), 1997 April 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8895)
    Support to increase male enrollment from the area served by the college, and to develop a small business incubator
    $270,000.00; $270,000.00
    Driver, Cyrus; Duncan, Cynthia M.; Booker, Queen E.
    Arkansas
  - Phillips University (05600784), 1956 June 29-1966 June 28 (Reel R0325)
  - Philosophical Research Center (07400065), 1973 November 01-1979 October 31 (Reel R2290)
    Strengthening cultural opportunities in greece through a series ofphilosophical research projects
    $332,390.00; $332,390.00
    Greece
  - Phoenix Color Corporation (10151346), 2001 May 01-2002 April 30 (Reel R9122)
    To publish a three-volume book entitled "The Microfinance Revolution: Sustainable Finance for the Poor"
    $38,325.00; $27,730.20
    Global; Microfinance; Poor--Credit
  - Phoenix Players Limited (10051638), 2000 July 01-2001 June 30 (Reel R8811)
    Support for repertory theatre presentations by amateur and semi-professional artists in kenya
    Akin Aina, Tade; Burris, Mary Ann
    Kenya; Performing Arts--Kenya; Theater--Kenya
  - Phoenix Players Limited (10151059), 2001 May 01-2003 April 30 (Reel R9000)
    Support for a new East African writers and performance series
    Africa, East; Performing Arts--Kenya
  - Phoenix Players Limited (10351419), 2003 July 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9072)
    For repertory theater presentations by amateur and semi-professional artists in Kenya
    Burnet, J. Robert; Nuvunga, Milagre
  - Phoenix Symphony Association (06600310), 1966 July 01-1976 June 30 (Reel R2923, Reel R4342)
  - Physical Research Laboratory (07850526), 1978 May 26-1979 May 25 (Reel R2951)
    Provision of equipment for thermoluminescence laboratory to be used for archaeological dating
    $9,500.00; $9,396.04
    Joshi, V. C.
  - Physical Research Laboratory (08850716), 1988 February 29-1989 August 31 (Reel R5837, Reel R5966)
    Support for upgrading the thermoluminescence dating laboratory for archeological research
    $46,500.00; $46,500.00
    Zurbuchen, Mary Sabina
  - Physical Research Laboratory (09250532), 1992 February 01-1993 February 01 (Reel R7049)
    Partial support for an international symposium on the "evolution of deserts" at ahmedabad
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (08750755), 1987 July 01-1988 June 30 (Reel R5568, Reel R5572)
    Start-up support to build a membership base for physicians for human rights
    Picken, Margo
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (08800872), 1988 July 01-1997 June 30 (Reel R7442)
    Support for work of physicians for human rights
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; International Affairs Program [IA]
    $1,190,000.00; $1,190,000.00
    Global; Human rights; Physicians--Societies
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (09750809), 1997 April 01-1999 March 31 (Reel R8001)
    Support for a project on the health impact on immigrants of welfare reform legislation
    Higashi, Taryn
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (10051203), 2000 April 01-2003 March 31 (Reel R8947)
    Partial support for research and dissemination of a report on racial and ethnic disparities in health care
    Silliman, Jael Miriam
    United States; Health surveys -- United States; Health and race -- United States; Minorities--Health and hygiene--United States
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (10251450), 2002 June 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R8988)
    To complete a survey of maternal mortality in Afghanistan in the context of the U.S. response to the September 11 attacks
    Afghanistan
  - Physicians for Human Rights, Inc. (10350897), 2003 April 01-2004 March 31 (Reel R9093)
    For a national advocacy campaign on global HIV/AIDS
    Cox, Larry; Winters, David
  - Physicians for Human Rights-Israel (10250780), 2002 April 01-2004 March 31 (Reel R9131)
    To promote the right of equal access to health care for vulnerable populations in Israel and Palestinians in the Occupied Territories
    Gaza; Israel; West Bank; West Bank
  - Physicians for Reproductive Choice and Health (10251704), 2002 August 01-2004 January 31 (Reel R9060)
    To develop its fundraising Web-site development capacity and for polling research and a multi-media project to improve its pro-choice message development and public outreach
    Floyd, Virginia Davis
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility (09951095), 1999 May 01-2002 April 30 (Reel R8939)
    Support for a public education campaign on nuclear abolition and environmental problems related to nuclear weapons materials
    United States; Global; Security (Law), International; Peace; Nuclear Disarmament--Global; Environmental education -- Global
  - Piact (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) (07800238), 1978 January 01-1980 December 31 (Reel R3619)
    Support of activities of a coordinating committee and secretariat
    Population [POP]
  - Piact (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) (08100700), 1981 August 01-1984 May 31 (Reel R4794, Reel R5332)
    Support for a contraceptive safety research awards program
    Bangladesh [ASIA/BA]; Population [POP]
    $142,000.00; $129,457.33
  - Piact (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) (08100933), 1981 October 01-1988 March 31 (Reel R6671)
    Support for planning, feasibility studies and technical assistance to implement foundation pri for ldc health technology transfer
    Atkinson, Linda E.
  - Piact (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) (08150480), 1981 June 01-1982 May 31 (Reel R3625)
    Support for an experiment on sex stereotyping in informational materials for non-literates
    $9,750.00; $9,750.00
  - Piact (Program for the Introduction and Adaptation of Contraceptive Technology) (08201076), 1982 October 01-1988 July 31 (Reel R5695)
    Support for an information service on introduction of new drugs and devices for family planning and reproductive health
    $303,000.00; $303,000.00
    Barzelatto, Jose
  - Piact De Mexico, A.C. (07950686), 1978 May 01-1980 June 30 (Reel R2786, Reel R5330)
    Support for printing and distribution of research studies on the use of contraceptive products
    $8,100.00; $8,100.00
    Cleaves, Peter S.; Perkin, Gordon W.
  - Piact De Mexico, A.C. (08150039), 1980 October 01-1981 October 31 (Reel R4045, Reel R5330)
    Cleaves, Peter S.
  - Pickman Consulting Group, Inc. (08500361), 1985 April 01-1988 August 31 (Reel R5599)
    Support for project to improve employment conditions of home care workers
    Urban Poverty Program [UP]; Office Of Program-Related Investments [PRI]
    $871,000.00; $871,000.00
    Lanigan, John
    United States; Milwaukee (Wis.); New York (N.Y.); San Diego (Calif.)
  - Pick-Up Performance Company, Inc. (09051107), 1990 September 01-1991 June 30 (Reel R6240)
    Partial support for a new work done in collaboration with four theater companies
  - Piedmont University Center Of North Carolina, Incorporated (06800336), 1968 September 01-1971 August 31 (Reel R1894)
    Program of internships in educational administration
    $69,750.00; $48,795.45
  - Piegan Institute (10101687), 2001 September 01-2003 August 31 (Reel R9046)
    For a community-based program to preserve and revitalize the Blackfeet language
    KC & F - Office of the Vice President; Media Arts and Culture
    Wilson, Kenneth; Pwono, Damien M.
    Montana; Siksika language; Sihasapa Indians
  - Pierce County, Washington (09201323), 1992 October 01-1993 December 31 (Reel R7905)
    Support for safe streets campaign (007)
    United States; Washington
  - Piermont Conservation Commission (07350887), 1973 October 03-1974 October 02 (Reel R1434)
    Inventory of town lands including abandoned roads & rights-of-way:basis for further work in open space protection & resource mgmt.
    $750.00; $570.38
  - Pilipina Inc. (09151279), 1991 August 15-1993 August 15 (Reel R6559, Reel R6755)
    Support to strengthen the capacity of women to improve development planners' responsiveness to gender issues
  - Pilipina Inc. (09950132), 1999 January 01-2000 June 30 (Reel R8811)
    Sup to formulate a women's agenda, to conduct orientations to local governance, & to prov leadership training for women in 3 cities
    Philippines; Local government--Philippines; Women--Political activity--Philippines; Civil society -- Philippines -- Citizen participation
  - Pilipino Bayanihan, Inc. (07600422), 1976 July 01-1978 June 15 (Reel R2872)
    Partial administrative support to a filipino american community development corporation
    $25,000.00; $18,700.00
  - Pinchot Institute (09600432), 1996 February 01-1998 January 31 (Reel R7191)
    Support for research, policy analysis, and meetings on sustainable community forestry in the united states
  - Pinchot Institute (09800123), 1997 October 01-2000 February 28 (Reel R8278)
    Support for research, policy analysis, and meetings on sustainabl e community forestry in the united states
    United States; Sustainable forestry--United States
  - Pinchot Institute (10002020), 2000 March 01-2004 February 29 (Reel R9160)
    United States; Conservation of natural resources -- United States; Community forests -- United States -- Congresses; Sustainable forestry--United States--Congresses
  - Pinchot Institute (10100466), 2001 January 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9013)
    A review of the forest management practices of 30 U.S. Native-American tribes and pre-assessment of their possibilities for certified sustainable forestry
    United States; Sustainable forestry--United States; Forests and forestry -- United States -- Certification; Indians of North America -- Employment
  - Pinchot Institute (10101427), 2001 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8860)
    For coordination, communications, monitoring and capacity building to enhance the involvement of local communities in forest restoration work for fire management
    United States; Forests and forestry -- United States; Conservation of natural resources -- United States
  - Pinchot Institute (10300280), 2002 December 01-2004 November 30 (Reel R9090)
    To coordinate and promote the certification of tribal lands in the United States
  - Pioneer Human Services (09701282), 1997 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R9130)
    Support for study of how to work more effectively with large corporations as purchasers of products
    Seattle (Wash.) (Wash.)
  - Pioneer Human Services (09701284), 1997 July 01-2000 June 30 (Reel R8925)
    Support for measurement of impact of supported work program
  - Pioneer Human Services (10050241), 1999 December 01-2000 May 31 (Reel R8370)
    To stage a meeting to identify synergies among the fields of workforce development, enterprise development, and regional economic development
    United States; Poor--Employment--United States; Microfinance--United States; Job creation; Community development -- Congresses
  - Pir-Center for Policy Studies (09751907), 1997 September 01-1999 February 28 (Reel R7996)
    Support for a project on nuclear nonproliferation and russia
  - Pitcairn Environmental Conservation Commission (07450107), 1973 November 30-1975 May 29 (Reel R1399)
    Preparation of a natural resources inventory of the town for efforts in environmental planning and resource management
    $2,375.00; $2,375.00
  - Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development Inc. (09000227), 1990 November 29-2000 November 28 (Reel R9124)
    Loss reserve fund
  - Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development Inc. (09001455), 1990 October 01-1995 September 30 (Reel R7469)
    Partial support to strengthen system of core operating support and technical assistance to cdc's in pittsburgh, pa
    $1,200,000.00; $1,200,000.00
    Anglin, Roland; Roman, Ruth
  - Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development Inc. (09900965), 1999 May 01-2000 April 30 (Reel R8684)
    To develop multineighborhood collaborations for community and economic development in pittsburgh
    Anglin, Roland
    United States; Community development -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh (Pa.); Community development corporations -- United States
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (06000239), 1960 June 02-1964 May 31 (Reel R0213)
    Team approach to improving education of in-migrant, transient pupils in depressed areas
    $528,400.00; $528,400.00
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (06500075), 1964 December 18-1968 June 17 (Reel R1779, Reel R1780)
    Improvement and expansion of education opportunities in pittsburgh schools, with emphasis on disadvantaged students
    $2,485,000.00; $2,465,286.58
    Bohrson, Ralph G.; Feldman, Marvin J.
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (06700529), 1967 July 01-1968 January 31 (Reel R1869, Reel R1870)
    Planning the great high schools program in pittsburgh
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (08201071), 1982 August 01-1991 June 30 (Reel R6279)
    Partial support to plan & evaluate schenley high school teacher center & to extend its outcomes to all pittsburgh high schools
    $1,020,000.00; $1,020,000.00
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (08251173), 1982 October 15-1983 October 14 (Reel R4654)
    City high school recognition program grant for south high school for school improvement activities
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools (08801102), 1988 September 01-1991 October 31 (Reel R6263)
    Support to plan the development of selected schools as clinical training sites for prospective teachers
    $179,600.00; $179,600.00
    Meade, Edward J.; Hatton, Barbara R.
  - Pittsburgh Regional Planning Association (05800380), 1958 October 07-1965 June 03 (Reel R2522, Reel R3006)
    Distribution abroad of published reports resulting from the economic study of the pittsburgh region
    $259,500.00; $259,500.00
  - Pittsburgh Theological Seminary (10100676), 2000 November 01-2003 October 31 (Reel R9147)
    Support for the Seminary's Center on Business, Religion and Public Life to foster public awareness and understanding of critical issues in contemporary society
    United States; Civil society -- United States; Social responsibility of business
  - Pittsfield Conservation Commission (07350859), 1973 September 27-1975 March 26 (Reel R1423)
    Preparation and initial implementation of a development plan for adjacent tracts of parkland along onota lake
    $3,250.00; $3,250.00
    Massachusetts
  - Pittsford Conservation Commission (07350467), 1973 May 25-1974 November 24 (Reel R1421)
    Ecological survey of town's natural areas for open space conservation and land use planning
    $1,250.00; $1,250.00
  - Pittstown Environmental Commission (07350889), 1973 October 03-1976 December 31 (Reel R1424)
    Environmental resources inventory of town as basis for efforts in open space protection, land use planning, & water resources mgmt.
    $3,050.00; $2,530.38
  - Pitzer College (09001163), 1990 September 01-1992 August 31 (Reel R6396)
    To improve race relations and address diversity issues (014)
  - Plainfield Conservation Commission (07350466), 1973 May 25-1974 May 24 (Reel R1421)
    Natural resources inventory emphasizing community participation to improve management of town's natural resources
    $750.00; $750.00
    Connecticut
  - Plaistow Conservation Commission (07450130), 1973 December 13-1975 June 12 (Reel R1399)
    Conduct surveys, title searches, & related preparatory work to manage open lands owned or being acquired by the town
    $1,625.00; $1,625.00
  - Plan of Action for Challenging Times (Pact) (06900243), 1969 March 01-1970 February 28 (Reel R1627, Reel R1628)
    Program to increase negro enrollment through college-campus visits by prospective students
    $10,000.00; $4,290.46
  - Plan Sierra (08150494), 1981 June 02-1982 December 02 (Reel R4055)
    Support for the design of a women's income-generating program in a rural section of the dominican republic
    $4,250.00; $4,250.00
    Dominican Republic
  - Plan Sierra (08450199), 1984 January 01-1984 September 30 (Reel R4256)
    Comprehensive evaluation of plan sierra's activities during the past five years
  - Plan Sierra (08550199), 1985 February 06-1985 August 06 (Reel R5134)
    Restructuring plan sierra's actvities over the next decade in the dominican republic
    $5,250.00; $5,250.00
  - Plan Sierra (08601047), 1986 October 28-1991 July 31 (Reel R6237)
    Applied research on alternative production systems in the highlands of the dominican republic
    Developing Country Programs [DCP]; Latin America & The Caribbean [LAC]
    $146,550.00; $146,550.00
  - Plan Sierra (09150609), 1991 March 01-1992 March 01 (Reel R7431)
    Support for evaluation and planning process for future programs of plan sierra
    Rural Poverty & Resources Program [RPR]; Developing Country Programs [DCP]; Latin America & The Caribbean [LAC]
    Campbell, Elizabeth C.; Sanborn, Cynthia
    Dominican Republic; Global
  - Plan Sierra (09300761), 1993 June 01-1999 May 30 (Reel R8094)
    Support for an income generation program for rural women in the dominican republic
  - Planned Parenthood Association Of Maryland, Inc. (06800200), 1968 March 01-1971 February 28 (Reel R2229)
    Supp. For an educ. And contraceptive service prog. For teenagers in coop. With baltimore urban league and johns hopkins univ.
    $250,000.00; $247,687.64
    Wickham, Robert S.
  - Planned Parenthood Association Of Maryland, Inc. (07650299), 1976 May 03-1976 August 02 (Reel R1229, Reel R4158)
    Support of a workshop on "strategies to introduce population studies into a school system."
    $8,220.00; $8,220.00
  - Planned Parenthood Association Of Maryland, Inc. (07750458), 1977 June 14-1978 September 30 (Reel R2626)
    A training program in in-school population education for u.s. School districts (ulpei)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (06600453), 1966 October 18-1977 December 31 (Reel R2833, Reel R2834, Reel R3033)
    General support of the center for family planning program development
    Population [POP]; Office Of Vice President -Finance & Administration; National Affairs [NA]
    $2,700,000.00; $2,700,000.00
    Berresford, Susan V. (Susan Vail); Teitelbaum, Michael S.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (06700011), 1966 November 16-1967 November 15 (Reel R1018)
    Publication and distribution of the proceedings of the 1965-66 meetings of the american assoc. Of planned parenthood phys.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (06700031), 1966 December 12-1967 December 11 (Reel R1018)
    International planned parenthood eighth international conference, santiago, chile, april 1967
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (07500340), 1975 July 01-1977 December 31 (Reel R2711)
    To conduct an intensive study of public policy issues related to the delivery of abortion services
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (07750565), 1977 March 15-1978 March 14 (Reel R1270)
    For publication expenses of a report "11 million teenagers-what can be done about the epidemic of adolescent pregnancies in the us
    Berresford, Susan V. (Susan Vail); Saario, Terry; Sweeney, William O.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (08700294), 1987 February 15-1987 August 14 (Reel R5468)
    Support for the media component of the teen pregnancy prevention program
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (08900924), 1989 July 01-1991 June 30 (Reel R5947)
    Support for university-based conferences on increased options for reproductive choices. (rhg)
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; Urban Poverty Program [UP]
    Barzelatto, Jose; Zeitlin, June H.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (09751697), 1997 July 01-1998 March 31 (Reel R7645)
    Support to plan the federation's diversity initiative
    Marcelo, Alexandrina B.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of America (09801614), 1998 July 01-2001 June 30 (Reel R8525)
    9upport to implement the federation's diversity initiative
    Winters, David
    United States; Diversity in the workplace -- United States
  - Planned Parenthood Federation Of Nigeria (07400071), 1973 December 13-1974 December 12 (Reel R1238, Reel R4308)
    Support for a population information and education campaign directed toward men
    DeSweemer, Cecile C.; Goodwillie, Susan R.
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of Nigeria (08953051), 1989 August 22-1993 June 30 (Reel R6737, Reel R7351)
    Support for an integrated family planning, health education and income generation program in southern nigeria
    $21,000.00; $18,051.88
  - Planned Parenthood of Arkansas, Inc. (08650456), 1986 May 01-1987 April 30 (Reel R5295, Reel R5302)
    To increase public awareness of issues relating to delivery of reproductive health care & children's health services in ark (rhg)
    $48,200.00; $48,200.00
    Harkavy, Oscar; Zeitlin, June H.
  - Planned Parenthood Of New York City, Inc. (06800770), 1968 August 06-1970 August 05 (Reel R1163)
    Provision of technical assistance to government agencies in family planning
  - Planned Parenthood Of New York City, Inc. (07000471), 1970 July 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R1702)
    Study on the relationship between hormonal contraception and cervical cancer
    $300,000.00; $299,317.04
  - Planned Parenthood of New York City, Inc. (08100052), 1980 November 01-1989 April 30 (Reel R6017)
    General support for family planning activities and project support for a public policy manual (rhg)
    National Affairs [NA]; Population [POP]; Urban Poverty Program [UP]; Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]
    Harkavy, Oscar; Miller, Shelby H.
    United States; New York (N.Y.); New York (State)
  - Planned Parenthood of New York City, Inc. (10001601), 2000 July 01-2003 June 30 (Reel R8951)
    Core support for the margaret sanger center international to advance reproductive rights, sexual health, and gender equity
    Global; Women--Health and hygiene--Global; Women's rights--Global
  - Planned Parenthood of New York City, Inc. (10101210), 2001 May 01-2002 April 30 (Reel R8800)
    For the initial phase of a national campaign to expand public debate and understanding of comprehensive sexuality education
    United States; Sex instruction--United States--Information services; Sexual health -- United States -- Information services; Sex--Study and teaching
  - Planning Assistance, Inc. (07650459), 1976 July 01-1977 January 31 (Reel R1461)
    To conduct a conference of legal services/legal aid leaders to plan for the future of the legal services corporation
    $5,500.00; $5,500.00